News from Qingzhou said
青州的消息传过来了
your son was bold enough
你儿子色胆包天
to run the risks
竟然
for kidnapping Consort of Jing'an.
把靖安王妃给掳走了
Lord of Jing'an smashed his Buddhist Hall in anger.
靖安王是一怒之下砸了佛堂
He also hired Wang Mingyin,
还请了天下十一
No. 11 in the world,
王明寅
to assassinate your son.
出手刺杀
I'm impressed
倒是没想到
you had Li Chungang
你竟然把李淳罡
protect him.
都请出来了
Your son threatened Lord of Jing'an with his consort,
你儿子以王妃要挟
he could do nothing except for letting him go.
靖安王只能放他离去
But now,
可这下子
North Liang will
你们北椋
feud with Qingzhou.
和青州的仇可就结深了
Lots of people hate North Liang,
恨北椋的人多了去了
we can take it if Zhao Heng does it, too.
不差一个赵衡
Your son
你说世子
is preposterous.
如此荒唐
How do you feel about it?
你怎么想啊
It doesn't matter what I feel.
我没什么可想的
It matters what
那得看看
His Majesty feels.
陛下怎么想
His Majesty feels pleased.
陛下很高兴
In his opinion,
如此荒唐的世子
such a preposterous heir
对陛下来说
is perfect for North Liang.
很适合北椋
Then tell me
那你说说
when His Majesty
这陛下
wants to see me?
打算什么时候见我呀
Be patient.
等等
Wait for several more days.
再等等
Your son has left Qingzhou for Yuzhou.
你儿子出青州过豫州
He'll soon arrive at Jiangnan of Yangzhou.
很快就到泱州江南道了
Fengnian
凤年这孩子
values family and friends.
重情
He always wants to visit his big sister.
老想去看他那个大姐
Have you heard the news
江南的消息
from Jiangnan?
你知道了
Staying in the capital,
我人在京城
my eyes are blindfolded and my ears are covered.
眼瞎耳聋的
How can I know anything?
我能知道什么
It's said...
听说
your eldest daughter
你的大女儿在江南道
is riotous in Jiangnan.
行事放荡
She has an affair with others.
与别人私通
The Lu Family has filed the suits
卢家把状子
to His Majesty.
都递到圣上驾前了
What a superb move!
这一步绝了
Grand Commander,
上柱国呀
you didn't notice the hidden danger of killing.
你没留意杀机暗藏
You'll definitely lose
这局棋
the game.
你输定了
It's hopeless.
没救了
Do you know
你知道
what kind of player is the most difficult?
什么样的棋手最可怕吗
Calculate ten steps before he takes one step.
一步十算
Seize the initiative before his opponent does.
料敌先机
The player that messes up the game is the most difficult.
搅局的棋手最可怕
It doesn't count. Let's play another game.
不算 重来
It's getting late. I have to go.
时候不早了 我先走了
You're not going.
哪儿去
Tell you what,
我告诉你
if I don't have three straight wins today,
今天我要不连胜你三局
you're not going anywhere.
你哪儿都去不了
I've already made the bed for you.
被窝都给你准备好了
- Come on. - I...
来吧来吧
- Amitabha.
阿弥陀佛
Lady Zhihu.
小姐
What are you doing?
你做什么
The Lu Family has a clean and upright reputation,
卢家门风清正
not expecting it to be ruined
到头来
by such a loose woman like you.
被你这个放荡女坏了家风
Xu Zhihu,
徐脂虎
rumors of you seducing men
你在外面勾引男人
have spread around the whole city.
闹得全城皆知
You're indeed shameless.
简直是不知羞耻
Do you envy me?
羡慕吗
You...
你
You shameless slut.
你这个无耻荡货
You pathetic thing.
可怜哪
No man wants you
你怕是想做荡货
even if you want to be a slut.
也没人要
I must rip your mouth off.
我撕了你这个嘴
How dare you!
做什么
Let go.
你放开我
Er'qiao.
二乔
Step aside.
让开
Let go of me.
放开我
Didn't you want to rip my mouth off?
不是要撕了我的嘴吗
Help yourself.
请吧
You don't think I dare to do so, do you?
你以为我不敢是吧
I bet you dare not.
我就赌你不敢
Will you do it or not?
动不动手啊
I have a book to read.
书还没有看完呢
It's a tragedy to have such a woman like you
卢家娶了你这种女人
marry into the family.
简直是家门不幸
Lady Zhihu,
小姐
the Lu Family is going too far.
卢家人越来越过分了
Why do you still smile?
您还笑啊
Of course I'm smiling.
我当然要笑了
I'm in a very good mood today.
我今天心情特别好
My brother is coming to see me.
因为我弟弟要来了
By my reckoning,
这么一算
it takes Fengnian two more days
应该再有两天
to arrive at Yangcheng.
凤年就到阳城了吧
Here we are.
终于到了
Ask for directions to the Lu Family
进城先问问
after we get in.
卢家怎么走
Your Highness.
世子
Should we wait for others to catch up with us?
要不等一下后边的马车
I'm going to visit my sister first.
我先去找我大姐
They can meet when they arrive.
让他们后边会合
Your Highness.
世子
What's up?
怎么了
Mr. Li said he was hungry.
李前辈说他饿了
Sure.
也是
It was a long journey.
这一路舟车劳顿
We've had a long day.
确实辛苦了
No hurry.
那先不着急
Let's find a restaurant
进城找个酒家
and have a square meal
大家吃饱了喝足之后
before we visit the Lu Family.
再去卢家
OK.
好
Your Highness.
世子
I've sent my men to pick up Mr. Li.
已经去接李前辈他们了
They'll arrive later.
车马慢了些
Let's eat first.
咱们先吃
All right.
也好
Let's order.
先点吃的
Then we'll ask for directions.
一会儿问路
Yeah. OK.
好
Hey, guys.
二位
I heard
我听说啊
the son of Lord of North Liang
北椋世子
is coming to Yangcheng
要来阳城
to visit his elder sister.
探望他大姐
The brother is ignorant
这一个是不学无术
while the sister is shameless.
一个是不知廉耻
They are
这对姐弟
the same kind of people.
还真是一类人哪
I heard
我听说啊
Mr. Chengzhai's wife
这诚斋先生的夫人
called Xu Zhihu
将徐脂虎骂作是
a whore.
两脚香炉
The rumors
这件事啊
have reached the capital.
京城都知道了
You know what,
你是有所不知啊
a concubine in the palace
在宫里有个娘娘
is of the same clan as Mr. Chengzhai's wife.
跟诚斋先生的夫人是同族
According to the family hierarchy,
按辈分算啊
Mr. Chengzhai's wife is one of her nieces.
娘娘叫她一声侄女
Xu Zhihu is such a dissolute woman.
徐脂虎她这般浪荡
How could the Lu Family
他卢家这点脸面
face other people?
往哪放啊
Tell me about
卢家的事
the Lu Family.
说给我听听啊
I was just thinking
我就是在想
Xu Xiao is the kind of man
徐骁这样的人
who calculates ten steps before he takes one.
走一步他能算十步
Why did he allow us
他为什么同意
to follow Xu Fengnian?
我们跟着徐凤年东行
I'm always afraid that
我总觉得
we'll become victims of his tricks.
我们也会变成他手里的弃子
Being afraid won't do you any good.
现在怕也没用
Let's wait and see first.
等事情临头了再说吧
By the way,
对了
why don't you take the carriage
你今天怎么不坐在
in front of us today?
前面那辆马车里
God of Sword snores heavily?
一代剑神还打呼噜
It's too noisy.
吵死了
I don't understand.
我也不明白了
The two little fellas
那两个小家伙
always jump about around me.
在我边上上蹿下跳
They seem to fear nothing.
天不怕地不怕
Why are they as good and quiet
怎么一到李前辈跟前
as kittens when they're around Mr. Li?
乖得跟小猫一样
The old man is highly skilled in martial arts.
那老头武功高
He can keep them under control.
镇得住它们
That is to say,
所以说
it's useful to be skilled in martial arts.
武功高还是有用
With numerous martial artists,
当年西楚高手如云
West Chu was still destroyed.
最后还不是灭国了
That was because North Liang was too strong.
那是北椋太可怕
We had the upper hand
国战初始
at the beginning of the war.
咱们楚国还是占了上风
I heard
我听说
many generals of Liyang were killed.
杀了离阳朝不少大将
The legitimate son of the Lu Family was captured
当年卢家嫡子领军被擒
and was put to death by my father.
被父王赐死了
Which family?
哪个卢家
The Lu Family in Yangcheng,
你说阳城这个
Xu Zhihu's husband's family?
徐脂虎的婆家
They must bear a deep grudge against you.
那跟你不是深仇大恨啊
They don't know my identity.
他们又不知道我身份
Don't worry.
别担心
Sir.
前辈
What's up?
怎么
Have we got to the restaurant?
到酒楼了
Mansion of Lu is not far.
卢家就在附近
Would you like to eat there?
前辈可以在卢家用饭
It's fine.
我都行
Call me when we arrive.
到了叫我
Please take care of everyone
到了卢家之后
when you're at the mansion.
麻烦前辈帮我照顾好大家
And
还有
don't expose Jiang Ni's identity to the family.
千万别让卢家知道姜泥的身份
Don't you come with us?
你不跟着去
I'm going to Jiangxin County
我要去江心郡
to meet someone surnamed Liu.
找一个姓刘的人
Are you going to kill him?
要杀人
I'm going to figure out
要弄清楚
what's his relationship with my sister.
他跟我姐到底什么关系
Don't you know the relationship
刘先生和徐脂虎什么关系
between Mr. Liu and Xu Zhihu?
你们都还不知道啊
Do they have an affair?
是有了私情吗
What kind of person is Liu?
刘先生是何等人物
He has literary talent
文采惊世
and profound learning inherited by his family.
家学渊源
The slut ran into him
这荡货
at Baoguo Temple
之前在报国寺遇上了
and shamelessly seduced him.
就没脸没皮地勾引人家才子
He was contemptuous of her.
刘先生嗤之以鼻
(Gentry of Jiangnan Liu Liting) He simply ignored her.
根本就不理睬她的
Coincidentally,
然后可巧
(Liu Liting's wife) Mr. Liu's wife came upon them.
被这刘先生的夫人给撞见了
Liu's wife is well connected.
这刘妻可不得了啊
It's said she is related to a concubine in the palace.
听说跟娘娘都是亲戚关系
She is Her Grace's niece.
听说娘娘叫她侄女
You don't say.
那可不是吗
How can she put up with such a slut?
怎么能容得下这种荡妇啊
Do you know what she did?
你们猜怎么着
She slapped her directly in the face.
直接一个巴掌就打上去了
She worked off her anger.
打得是解气
Now everyone in Yangcheng knows
如今阳城人尽皆知
our family have such a daughter-in-law.
我们卢家有这么一个儿媳妇了
It isn't true.
不是这样的
It was not the case.
当时并非如此
Do you try to deny it for her?
你还想替她抵赖
Let's go.
走走走
People have a sense of natural justice.
公道自在人心
Never mind.
算了
It's natural that
受委屈被误解
being wronged and misunderstood makes you sad.
心里自然会很难过
But remember,
但是你要记住
don't cry over it.
千万别哭
Tears should only
眼泪啊
(Elegant and Refined) be shed for your loved ones.
要留给心里最重要的人
Remember?
知道了
Son of Lord of North Liang,
北椋世子
Xu Fengnian,
徐凤年
drove by Yangcheng.
车驾过阳城
Please...
请
I've inquired about it.
打听过了
It's Liu Liting's mansion.
这里确是刘黎廷的住处
How's his reputation?
这人口碑如何
People say he writes good articles.
都说他文章不错
He's been talented since he was a child.
从小就很有才名
What about his family?
家族呢
In Yangzhou,
刘家在泱州
his family is only regarded as second-class.
只能算是二等末流士族
That doesn't feel right.
那就不对了
What do you mean?
哪里不对
The Lu Family is a first-class family.
卢家在泱州是一等一的名门
Lu Daolin, the head of the Lu Family,
家主卢道林
is the Minister of Rites
官拜礼部尚书
and the principal of the national college.
还在京城兼国子监右祭酒
With such a status,
这等人物
even Zhang Julu has to
就是张巨鹿撞见了
show some respect for him.
也要讲几分情面
How dare Liu Liting
他刘黎廷多大胆子
hook up with the daughter-in-law of the Lu Family?
敢惹卢家的媳妇
Your Highness.
世子
The whole city knows
全城都知道
it's Lady Zhihu who has crushes on Liu.
是小姐先动的心
Liu didn't hook up with her.
不是刘黎廷先招惹她
With my sister's status,
我姐何等的人物
how can she have crushes on such a man?
怎么可能看得上他
Love is not
这男女之事
reasonable.
谁又能说得清楚
Enough.
够了
Let's find out the truth.
真相如何一探便知
Shu Xiu.
舒羞
I'm counting on you.
看你的了
Who are you?
阁下是
I'm Lu Dongyang,
在下卢东阳
housekeeper of the mansion.
卢府管家
Nice to meet you.
卢管家好
Xu Fengnian, son of Lord of North Liang,
北椋世子徐凤年
drove by your city.
路经此地
We come to visit relatives.
专为探亲而来
(No Guests) What a coincidence.
这倒巧了
We don't receive guests today.
卢府今日不会客
Please go back.
各位请回
Pay a visit another day.
择日再来
we've just
我等
arrived at Yangcheng.
初到阳城
We have no place to stay.
并无住处
It's none of my business.
这与我何干
Would you please do us a favor and inform Lady Zhihu?
或者卢管家帮忙通报我家小姐
Xu Zhihu ruined the family tradition.
徐脂虎败坏家风
How does she have the face to receive guests?
有何颜面出来见人
Mr. Lu,
卢管家
whatever the truth is,
无论真相如何
please announce
还是麻烦卢管家
our arrival.
通报一声
What're you doing?
你干吗
The guy humiliated us on purpose.
这家伙故意羞辱人
It has nothing to do with you.
关你什么事啊
I can't bear it.
看不过去啊
Oh, dear.
哎呀
Have you forgotten the grudge the Lu Family held against your country?
你忘了卢家和楚国的仇了
How dare you get out?
还往外跑
Aren't you afraid they'll recognize you?
你不怕他们认出来
I was young at that time.
那时候我才多大
They won't recognize me.
谁认得出来
It's said North Liang is a wild land.
都说北椋荒蛮之地
You really know nothing about courtesy.
果真不懂礼数
Didn't I make it clear?
我说得还不够清楚吗
We don't receive guests today.
今日不会客
Why should I notice your arrival?
我通什么报
Wei Shuyang is such a coward.
这魏叔阳也是窝囊
How could he swallow the insult?
这都不发火
Since Xu's daughter married into Lu Family,
卢家和北椋结亲
they've become allies.
那就是天然的盟友
Considering the relationship between the two families,
魏叔阳要考虑两家关系
Wei Shuyang won't be reckless.
不会乱来的
Give me a blade.
借把刀
How dare you!
你好大的胆子
Don't be reckless.
别闹太大
This is Yangcheng,
这是阳城
not North Liang.
这不是你们北椋
In North Liang, we have a simple rule
北椋行事待人
to treat people.
其实一直都很简单
If you treat me with courtesy,
待我以礼
I'll return you with courtesy.
还之以礼
If you treat me with blades,
待我刀兵
I'll return you with those, too.
还之刀兵
Mr. Lu, please forgive her.
卢管家莫怪
Open the door.
开门
Hurry up.
快快快
Open the side door and let them in.
快开侧门让他们进去
Open the front door.
开中门
requires the head's permission.
要家主张口才成
I can't make the decision.
我真做不了这个主
Do you mind if I
要不
go to ask for permission?
我去给你问问
Don't bother.
不用麻烦了
Remove the front door.
把中门给我拆了
Give it to me.
来给我吧
Don't follow me.
你就别跟着了
Get back to your work.
忙你的去吧
He is Liu Liting.
这人就是刘黎廷
Other scholars
其他读书人
usually keep away from the kitchen,
感觉君子远庖厨
but he would cook himself.
他倒肯亲自下厨
It's rare.
也算难得
Honey.
娘子啊
It's me.
是我
My sister won't have crushes on him.
我姐不会看上他
Why are you so sure?
世子如此确定
She's got someone in her mind.
我姐心里有人了
Is it her husband who died of illness?
卢家病死的公子
He is at
我姐心里的人
Mount Wudang.
在武当山
Mount Wudang?
武当山
Aren't there all Taoists?
那不都是道士吗
Get back to your work.
去办事吧
Here, honey.
来 娘子
Try this soup.
尝尝这个汤
I've cooked it for a long time.
我可是熬了很久的
Are you still angry?
还气呢
It's bad for your health.
气坏了身子就不好了
I'd better die of anger.
气死拉倒
You'll find it satisfactory, won't you?
刚好称了你的心
You're wrong about me.
我实在是冤枉啊
You know
你也知道
it was the slut who pestered me.
是那荡妇主动缠我
It was an unexpected calamity.
实在是无妄之灾
The woman is much younger than me.
那女子可比我年少
Honey.
娘子
I love you truly.
我对你是一片真情
How could I be attracted to that slut?
怎么会对那种荡妇动心呢
Why don't you believe me?
你怎么就不信我呢
That woman is shameless.
那女子不知廉耻
Don't see her again.
你以后少去见她
I won't.
不见不见
I avoid her like the plague.
避之不及
How would I see her?
怎会相见
Taste this.
尝尝
Don't be angry.
别生气
Madam hasn't started eating yet.
夫人还没动筷呢
Come when she finishes off.
等吃完了再来收拾
The servants become unruly now.
这些下人越发没有规矩了
Don't be upset.
别生气啊
I'll have a look.
我去看看
Who is it?
谁啊
Liu Liting, Mr. Liu.
刘黎廷 刘先生
Who is this?
这又是谁啊
How dare she come to our home?
都到家里来了
I don't know her, either.
我也不认识啊
How did you get in?
你是怎么进来的
What do you want?
你要做什么
It tastes good.
味道还挺好的
Liu Liting.
刘黎廷
What's going on exactly?
这到底怎么回事
Honey.
夫人夫人
Honey, cool down.
夫人息怒
I really don't know who she is.
我当真不知此女是谁
Who are you exactly?
你到底是什么人
How did you get in our mansion?
怎么进的府门
Get out...
你给我出
Honey.
夫人夫人
Cool down. Don't be angry.
息怒息怒 别生气
Don't be angry.
别生气
Get someone to take her and send her to the government.
叫人拿下送官衙
Yes. I'm going to get help.
好 我现在就去叫人
Madam, your hairpin is beautiful.
夫人簪子还挺漂亮的
What do you want?
你干什么
Miss, if you want money,
姑娘若是求财
let him go.
把人放了
We can talk about it.
一切好说
I don't want money.
我不要钱
I want a life.
只要命
Mr. Liu is of a great name.
刘先生的名声这么大
Why don't you lend me your life?
不如借命一用
We've never met each other before.
我与姑娘素不相识
Why do you hate me so much?
哪来的怨仇
I don't hate you,
你我并无仇怨
but I hate North Liang
可我和北椋
very much.
不共戴天
I have nothing to do with North Liang.
在下与北椋也并无干系
Xu Zhihu
徐脂虎
is Xu Xiao's daughter.
是徐骁的女儿
Then you should go to Mansion of Lu and kill her.
那你应该去卢府杀徐脂虎才对啊
The mansion is heavily guarded.
卢府戒备森严
Besides,
再说了
Lu Baijie, Sword Immortal of Tangxi,
卢家还有一个
is also in the mansion.
棠溪剑仙
I can't break in.
我也闯不进去
It's much brighter.
这可亮堂多了
Don't you think you've gone too far?
是不是闹得大了些
The more domineering we are, the more relieved the royal court will feel.
越跋扈京城那边越放心
If we're disciplined,
真守礼了
they'll fear us instead.
反受忌惮
After all, we represent His Highness.
毕竟是世子车驾
You shouldn't humiliate us.
岂能受辱
Let's get inside.
咱进去吧
Today,
今日
it was our fault to shut you out.
是卢府失了待客之道
I apologize
我替管家们
to you
给各位
on behalf of the housekeeper.
赔礼了
Baxiu Sword.
霸秀剑
You are...
你是
You're Sword Immortal of Tangxi,
你是棠溪剑仙
Lu Baijie.
卢白颉
In the presence of God of Sword,
李剑神面前
I feel unworthy of the name.
不敢提剑仙二字
I've heard the name of God of Sword for a long time.
晚辈已久闻剑神大名
Today, I venture to suggest you
今日斗胆
show me Snakes in Sleeves.
愿领教两袖青蛇
Let's have a competition on swordplay.
砥砺剑道
How do you know he is with us?
你怎知李剑神在此
Since the battle of Reed Marshes,
芦苇荡一战
God of Sword's valorous fame
李剑神威压四方
has spread throughout the world.
已传遍了江湖
Sir,
前辈
would you condescend to teach me?
可愿赐教
Qingniao.
青鸟
Lady Zhihu.
大小姐
Grandpa Wei.
魏爷爷
You came so soon.
来得这么快
Where's Fengnian?
凤年呢
He went to Jiangxin County.
他去江心郡了
He's such a fool.
这个傻瓜
Uncle.
小叔
What're you doing?
你这是
Being apart for a long time,
久别重逢
you should catch up first.
你们先叙旧吧
I got it.
我知道了
Lu Baijie is the only one
卢白颉是卢家人里边
who regards Xu Zhihu
唯一把徐脂虎
as a family member in the Lu Family.
当作自家晚辈的
It's not easy for you
姑娘要杀徐脂虎
to kill Xu Zhihu.
确实不容易
But, Miss,
女侠
you want to kill a member of the Xu Family,
你要杀的是徐家人
yet I'm from the Liu Family.
我可是姓刘啊
Everyone in Jiangnan knows that
如今江南谁不知道
you and Xu Zhihu are having an affair.
你和徐脂虎恋奸情热
By killing you,
杀了你
I'll let her know the taste of pain.
让她也尝尝心痛的滋味
Miss.
姑娘
Though the slut pestered my husband,
那贱人虽然痴缠外子
he despised her very much.
但外子却对其嗤之以鼻
They don't have an affair.
并无什么奸情
Why don't you escape?
夫人怎么不跑
A wife and her husband should live or die together.
夫妻本同命
How can I leave him?
我怎能弃他而去
You have such a good wife.
有这么好的夫人
All she said is true.
夫人说的都是真的
I have nothing to do with Xu Zhihu.
我与那徐脂虎并无牵连
I'm disgusted with her.
还对其厌恶有加
It doesn't matter how you feel about her.
你对她什么感觉不重要
The point is she loves you.
关键是她喜欢你
Killing you
所以杀了你
will make her feel pain.
她也一样心疼
Miss, have mercy on me.
女侠饶命
Shut up.
闭嘴
Honey, help me.
娘子救我
Miss,
姑娘
I'm related to a concubine in the palace.
我与宫里贵妃乃族亲
Have you thought about
姑娘行事
the consequences?
可想想后果
People don't think much
报仇的人
while seeking revenge.
不会想这么多
Wait. Wait.
等等
Miss.
女侠
Let me help you to kill Xu Zhihu.
我能帮你杀了徐脂虎
How can you do that?
怎么个帮法
The slut still has a fantasy about me.
那荡妇对我贼心不死
If I ask her out,
我约她私会
she'll definitely come out.
她定然会赴约
Why do you tread in muddy water?
这浑水你也蹚
Let me write a letter
我这就写信
and ask her out.
约徐脂虎出来
Look at me.
你看我
I'm so weak.
手无缚鸡之力
How can I escape?
怎会逃脱呢
It's right.
也对
Try to run away
你们可以逃走
or scream for help.
也可以大声叫喊
I don't think anyone would come to rescue you.
看看有没有人会来救你们
I dare not.
不敢不敢
Let me find a brush and some ink.
我寻笔墨
The words I'm about to say
接下来的话
mustn't be heard by her.
不能让她听到
What words?
什么话
The real relationship
我和徐脂虎之间
between Xu Zhihu and me.
真正的关系
Thank you.
多谢大小姐
Don't stand on ceremony.
不必多礼
I'm glad to see the people
能见到北椋府里来的人
from North Liang.
我心里高兴
Sit down.
坐吧
I've arranged accommodation for everyone.
其他人也都安排好了住处
Don't worry.
你放心就好
Fengnian
只是凤年
should come to see me first.
他应该先来见我呀
His Highness
世子
heard the rumors.
也是听了传闻之后
He wanted to find out the truth.
想要亲自去看看
What happened between me and Liu Liting
我和那刘黎廷之间
wasn't like what people made out.
并非坊间所说的那样
How come?
怎么说
It was you who pestered Xu Zhihu?
是你在纠缠徐脂虎
Yes, I did.
确实如此
Every time when Xu came out,
每逢徐脂虎出门
I would find a chance to run into her.
我总会找机会偶遇
I wrote her poets
送诗文
and complimented her beauty.
赞美色
I used a variety of tactics
各种手段用尽
and exhausted all mental efforts.
也算是费尽心机
If it were another woman,
换作其他女子
she would be moved.
总会动容
But Xu Zhihu was iron-hearted.
可偏偏这徐脂虎铁石心肠
She always kept a good distance from me.
始终将我拒之千里
What about Baoguo Temple?
那报国寺呢
That mild-mannered girl
窈窕淑女
is a good mate to a gentleman.
君子好逑
I am
我也是
mad about you.
一片痴心
Your wife happened to see you?
她恰好碰上你的夫人
It wasn't a coincidence.
不是巧合
She specially went to look for me.
她是专程来寻我的
And then?
然后呢
She didn't see me catching her sleeves.
她没瞧见我抓人衣袖
I kept my wits about me
我当时随机应变
and scolded Xu Zhihu for being lack of virtue
斥责徐脂虎不守妇道
and pestering me again and again.
屡次纠缠
You were pretty quick.
你反应倒是挺快的
I was out of option.
也是无奈之举
What happened next?
之后呢
My wife believed me.
内子还是相信我
She slapped Xu in anger.
一气之下动了手
How dare you strike me back?
你还敢还手
You treat me with blades, I'll return you with blades.
待我刀兵 还之刀兵
It's what the people of North Liang do.
北椋人向来如此
So,
所以
Xu Zhihu doesn't
我和徐脂虎之间
have any affection for me.
并无情意
The only thing she has towards me is probably hatred.
她对我恐怕只有恨意
Miss,
女侠
it won't hurt her at all
如果要杀我
if you kill me.
她并不会心痛
I don't understand.
还是不对
Since Xu was pestered by you,
既然是你纠缠徐脂虎
why didn't she clarify the rumors?
那她为什么不出来反驳
Well,
这点
I didn't figure it out myself.
我确实也想不明白
Perhaps...
或许
Perhaps she was
或许是她
too proud
孤傲清高
to clarify it?
不屑解释呢
Liu Liting has a literary fame
那个刘黎廷素有文名
while I am
而我呢
from North Liang.
出自北椋
People in Jiangnan
江南人把我们北椋人
regard us as monsters.
当作凶魔疯兽
Do you think anyone will believe me?
你觉得会有人相信我说的话吗
What about the Lu Family?
那卢家呢
You've married into the family.
你毕竟是嫁过来的
They should treat you differently.
他们对你应该不一样
The so-called marriage
说是嫁人
was just a deal
其实就是卢家
made by the Lu Family and North Liang.
和北椋的交易罢了
As soon as the deal is done,
交易成了
I'm of no use.
我也就什么都不是了
Why do you think they let me
要不当初怎么会找一个
marry a dying man?
快要病死的娶我呀
Lady Zhihu,
小姐
I'm sorry you are wronged.
受委屈了
Don't be.
不委屈
I'm willing to do so.
是我自己愿意的
It's good enough that North Liang sacrificed me
能用我自己换来北椋的盟友
in exchange for an ally.
我觉着挺好
I mean
我是说
the rumors about you and Liu Liting.
您和刘黎廷的传闻
A bunch of people I don't know defame me.
不认识的人毁我谤我
It has nothing to do with me.
与我何干呀
I don't feel like arguing with them at all.
我根本就懒得争辩
His Highness won't misunderstand you.
世子一定不会误解小姐的
I know.
我知道
He wants to
他呀
defend me against injustice.
怕是为我出气去了
They're just empty words.
空口白话
Why should I believe you?
我凭什么信你
I can swear to God.
刘某可以对天发誓啊
Can you compare to such a powerful family
卢家在江南什么地位
as Lu in Jiangnan?
你能比吗
Well...
这个
I can't.
这个比不了
Then why did you pester Xu Zhihu?
那你为何还要纠缠徐脂虎
Though she's a widow,
她虽是寡妇
she is still a member of the Lu Family.
但她也是卢家人
Weren't you afraid the rumors about you and her
你和她传出这些闲话
would offend the family?
不就得罪了卢家
Well...
这
Xu Zhihu is really beautiful.
徐脂虎确实美貌
So I'm attracted to her.
所以我对她动
So
为此
you risked your future for her?
你就用你的前途冒险
Do you think I'll believe you?
你觉得我能信吗
You can't explain it clearly, can you?
解释不清了
I think
我看
I'd better kill you.
还是杀了你算了
What's your feud with North Liang?
女侠到底和北椋结的什么仇啊
You don't get to ask questions.
你倒盘问起我来了
There're some things
有些事
I would never tell you
我要不知道女侠的身份
without knowing your identity.
我死也不会说出口
It doesn't hurt to tell you.
告诉你也无妨
I'm the princess of Chu.
我是楚国公主
The princess of West Chu?
西楚亡国公主
You want me to walk around
你就让我每天弄成这样
being dressed like this?
在府里走来走去
Do you still want to walk around?
你还想走来走去
This is Mansion of Lu.
这是卢府
You'd better hide in the room.
你就躲屋里别动了
You're overreacting.
那也太夸张了吧
Better than you get yourself killed.
总比丢了命好
Under my protection,
有我在
she won't get killed.
她的命不会丢
Thank you, sir.
多谢前辈
I can rest assured with your protection.
有前辈护佑就放心了
Xu Fengnian asked me to protect you.
是徐凤年叮嘱我护着你
You should thank him, girl.
要谢谢他吧 小丫头
I would never thank him.
谁要谢那家伙
Old man.
老头
Yes?
怎么了
Where's my Divine Token?
我的神符呢
I lent it to you.
那可是我借给你的
Have you lost it?
你给弄丢了
Be quiet.
小点声
Xu Fengnian
是徐凤年那个小子
borrowed it just now.
刚才借走了
He has no rights
我的匕首
to borrow my dagger.
他凭什么借
Why did he borrow it?
他借神符做什么
Do you recognize
这把匕首
the dagger?
认识吗
The national dagger of West Chu,
西楚传国匕首
Divine Token.
神符
You know it.
你倒是认识
According to historical records,
史书记载
the dagger
此匕首
may exchange for twelve cities.
可换十二城
I've heard of the precious dagger.
这等宝物我有所听闻
Are you really the princess of Chu?
你真的是西楚公主
Are you still alive?
你活到现在没有死
Do you wish me to die?
你希望我死了
I dare not.
不敢不敢
Now I got it.
那我知道了
Xu Xiao conquered Chu.
徐骁灭了楚国
Of course you hate them.
公主因此有恨理所当然
Please forgive me, Your Highness.
还请公主见谅
I heard that Xu Fengnian is about to arrive at Jiangnan.
听闻徐凤年快要到江南了
You showed up at this time.
公主此时出现
It makes me confused.
我难免有所疑惑
I came to Jiangnan this time
我这次来江南
in order to kill Xu Fengnian.
就是找机会杀了徐凤年
You're just extra points.
你不过就是个添头
I have the same goal as you.
我和公主目标是一样的
I'm against North Liang, too.
也是与北椋为敌呀
Please wait a minute.
公主稍等
Look at this.
公主您看
Imperial Academy?
翰林院
Was it from the capital?
京城的信
A good friend of mine
刘某的好友
is a scholar of Imperial Academy.
现在是翰林院的庶吉士
Was it his idea
败坏徐脂虎名声
to besmirch Xu Zhihu's reputation?
是他教你的
He said the court was always wary of North Liang.
他说朝廷向来忌惮北椋
After North Liang united with Jiangnan by marriage,
如今北椋与江南联姻
they became a sting in their heart.
更是心腹之患
If I blacken Xu Zhihu's name,
我若能败坏徐脂虎的声名
I may turn the Lu Family
说不好就能让卢家
against North Liang.
和北椋反目
Though doing so
虽然这么做
may offend the Lu Family,
会惹恼卢家
in the end, I may be appreciated by His Majesty.
可是说到底 简在帝心
When I go to the capital next time,
等我再去京城
I'll get a limitless future.
未来前程不可限量
Therefore,
所以
it was a complete conspiracy.
这从头到尾都是阴谋
Pestering Xu Zhihu was just a smoke bomb.
并不是什么君子好色
Don't call it a conspiracy.
怎么能说是阴谋呢
As a scholar, it's my duty to serve my country.
读书人为国效力总是应该的
Does she
这些事
know about these?
她知道吗
No, she doesn't.
并不知情
What did you say?
你刚刚说什么来着
Your wife happened to see you?
她恰好碰上你的夫人
It wasn't a coincidence.
不是巧合
She specially went to look for me.
她是专程来寻我的
I have a message sent to my wife
是我让人传的消息
before she hurried to Baoguo Temple.
才让内子赶来报国寺的
Then you took advantage of your wife's relative
然后利用你夫人同族的关系
and let the concubine in the palace
让宫里那位娘娘
help you to publicize it,
帮你大肆宣扬此事
so His Majesty would hear of your name.
这样你的名字就能被皇上听到
Liu Liting,
刘黎廷
how could you trick your own wife?
你连自己的夫人都算计
I just followed the trend.
顺势而为
Don't say that.
怎么能说是算计呢
Your Highness,
公主
do you believe me now?
这回该相信我了吧
I have the same goal as you.
我和公主的目标是一样的
We're both against North Liang.
都是与北椋为敌啊
As for that,
这么说来
you're right.
确实如此
You're really vicious.
可你也真够狠的
Xu Zhihu is ruined by you.
徐脂虎可真被你给毁了
The Lu Family has strict rules.
卢家家规森严
In my opinion,
按我的想法
it's best if the Lu Family exercise domestic discipline on her.
卢家最好能对她动家法
She may be beaten to death.
到时候死了都有可能
Unfortunately, Lu Baijie has been protecting her.
只可惜卢白颉一直护着她
It doesn't matter now.
不过没关系
We've got a chance.
咱们现在有机会了
What chance?
什么机会
We should figure out Xu Fengnian's schedule first.
如果能确定徐凤年的行程
Because of the rumors,
有我和徐脂虎的传闻
he would come to see me alone.
他定会单独见我
Then you take the opportunity to kill him.
到时候公主出手杀了此贼
You can take revenge for your country.
对你来说是报了国仇
As for me,
而对我来说呢
I can completely destroy
就能彻底毁了
the oath of alliance forged by the Lu Family and North Liang.
卢家和北椋的盟约
It satisfies both sides.
两全其美啊
You're brilliant.
厉害啊
No wonder you're a scholar.
真不愧是读书人
Who wrote the letter?
信是谁写的
Who are you?
你又是谁
Jin Lanting.
晋兰亭
I've never heard of him.
没听说过
There're many scholars in Imperial Academy.
翰林院庶吉士这么多
It's normal that you didn't hear of him.
世子没听说过也很正常
I want to know who he works for.
就不知道到底是谁的人
Zhang Julu,
张巨鹿
or someone else?
还是别人
It's hard to decide.
不好判断
He's got such devious means.
不过这手段倒是阴险
We must investigate him carefully later.
这个晋兰亭回头得好好查查
You did a great job just now,
你刚才做得不错
but there was a flaw.
但还是有破绽
When he said he was under instructions from the capital,
他说他受京城指派时
you shouldn't soften your stance so quickly.
你不应该这么轻易缓和下来
The people of Chu hate Xu Xiao,
楚人恨徐骁
but they hate the royal family even more.
更恨离阳皇室
When he said his wife is related
他说他夫人
to a concubine in the palace,
跟皇室贵妃同族
you should be tougher,
你态度要更强硬
which fitted your role better.
才符合扮演的身份
I'm not
我哪有世子
as thoughtful as you.
这么深的心思呀
Who the hell are you?
你们到底是什么人
I'm Xu Fengnian.
我是徐凤年
I heard you were going to kill me.
刚听说你要杀我
It doesn't matter, though.
这倒没什么
But you've crossed my bottom line
但想借卢家害死我姐
trying to kill my sister through the hands of the Lu Family.
这就到我底线了
You treat me with blades, I'll return you with blades.
待我刀兵者 还以刀兵
Liu Liting,
刘黎廷
you've brought ruin
是你自己选择
upon yourself.
给你带来的终局
Help!
来人哪
Your Highness.
世子
What about her?
她怎么办
She slapped my sister once.
她打过我姐一巴掌
My sister slapped her in return.
我姐也还了她一巴掌
We're even with her.
这事就算跟她没关系了
Just let her go?
就这么放了
Why don't we kill her?
要不杀了吧
It's easy.
顺手的事
Whatever we do,
做人做事
we shouldn't cross the bottom line.
还是要有点底线
What about his family?
家里的人怎么处理的
We just tied them up.
那些家人都只是被捆绑住
We didn't hurt them.
并无伤亡
Good.
好
Why do you shut his mouth?
怎么把嘴堵上了
Remove the gag.
拿掉
Help!
救命啊
The son of Lord of North Liang is killing people!
北椋世子徐凤年要杀人啦
- Just scream. - Xu Fengnian.
喊 接着喊
Xu Fengnian dares to lynch people.
徐凤年动用私刑
Is there any law in the country?
离阳朝王法何在
Is there any heavenly principle?
天理何在啊
He's right.
没错
I'm the son of Lord of North Liang, Xu Fengnian.
我就是北椋世子徐凤年
Everyone,
诸位
keep it in your mind.
把这名字给我记好了
Xu Fengnian,
徐凤年
you can't kill me.
你不能杀我
Of course, I can kill you if you try to kill other people.
你要杀人 人便杀你
It's the heavenly principle and justice.
这就是天理公道
I know I've made a mistake.
我知道错了
I'm willing to...
我愿意
I'm willing to work for you.
我愿意投效世子门下
You've lost your last bit of guts.
最后一点骨气也没保住
Go.
走
Get back to Yangcheng.
回阳城
Xu Fengnian!
徐凤年
- Xu Fengnian, let go of me! - It may kill him.
徐凤年你把我放开
You won't die a natural death.
徐凤年你不得好死
You just said he was in danger in Reed Marshes.
你刚才还说芦苇荡刺杀遇险
Now God of Sword isn't around him.
这会儿李剑神也不在身边
He went to Jiangxin County
此去江心郡
on the spur of the moment.
世子是临时起意
He won't be assassinated.
不会遇到刺杀的
I'm not just worried about him.
可我担心的还不仅仅是他
With so many guards around him,
他身边护卫众多
he was still attacked.
都还遇到刺杀
Huangman'er went to Mount Longhu alone.
那黄蛮儿孤身去了龙虎山
It must be more dangerous.
岂不是更加艰险
With extraordinary power, he can protect himself.
小王爷天生神力必能自保
He is just human after all.
再神力终也是人
I thought in the first place
我当初还以为
as long as I married into the Lu Family,
只要我嫁过来江南
they would stay safely in North Liang.
他们几个就能安稳地留在北椋
I didn't expect us
没想到
to be far apart
姐弟四个到头来
from each other in the end.
还是天各一方
Little buddy,
小兄弟
may I ask if this is Mount Longhu?
请问这是龙虎山吗
Which direction should I take going up the mountain?
请问上山该往哪边走
Thanks.
多谢
What are you looking at?
你在看什么
I'm waiting for the hawthorns.
等山楂
Hawthorns?
山楂
When the hawthorns are ripe,
等山楂熟了
I'll save them for my brother.
我要留给我哥吃
Who is your brother?
你哥是谁
Do you know him?
认识我哥
What's your family name?
你姓什么
Xu.
徐
Are you Xu Longxiang?
你是徐龙象
Yeah.
嗯
What a coincidence.
这么巧
It probably is fate.
这大概就是命吧